Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at our mobile phones but not the physical phone.
今天我们要聊聊我们的手机，但不是说手机本身。
Now we're going to talk about services that you can get for your mobile phone.
我们要讨论的是手机可以使用的服务。
Alright so in America and many other places you don't buy that little card with money
好的，在美国和很多其他地方，你不会买那种带钱的小卡片
on it.
来充值。
You actually have to pay every month for a service.
实际上，你每个月都要为服务付费。
So we're going to learn about this today.
所以今天我们就来学习这个。
Let's check out our dialogue.
让我们来看看对话。
Telco Mobile how can I help you?
Telco Mobile，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
是的，我想激活我的语音信箱服务。
Certainly sir.
当然可以，先生。
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services, call waiting
我们目前有一个特别优惠，包括语音信箱服务、呼叫等待
and also three-way calling.
还有三方通话。
Sure, that sounds great.
好的，听起来不错。
Are there any other fees?
还有其他费用吗？
Not at all.
完全没有。
No hidden fees or surcharges.
没有隐藏费用或附加费。
It is a flat monthly rate.
这是固定的月费。
Perfect.
太好了。
I also wanted to know if there's any call forwarding service.
我还想知道有没有呼叫转移服务。
I am usually out of town and would like my calls to be forwarded to a local number.
我经常出差，希望电话能转接到一个本地号码。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然有。
We can activate all these services in about an hour.
我们可以在大约一小时内激活所有这些服务。
Alright, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of these services on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们在“语言要点”部分看看这些服务。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So Marco the first word that I want to talk about today is this verb to activate.
那么Marco，今天我想谈的第一个词是动词“activate”。
That's right.
没错。
We have a verb here to activate and this means to make something start to work, to make something
这里有一个动词“activate”，意思是让某物开始工作，让某物
begin.
开始运作。
That's right.
没错。
So to turn on but you don't say hey can you activate the light?
所以是“打开”的意思，但你不能说“嘿，你能activate灯吗？”
You wouldn't say that.
你不会这么说。
You say can you turn on the light.
你会说“你能turn on灯吗”。
But to activate means to start a service.
但“activate”指的是启动一项服务。
That's right.
没错。
So this is what we want today.
所以这就是我们今天要做的。
We want to activate some services and the first one that we ask for is voicemail service.
我们想激活一些服务，第一个我们要求的是语音信箱服务。
Voicemail service.
语音信箱服务。
Now let's think about the words that make up this one word.
现在让我们想想组成这个词的单词。
Voicemail.
语音信箱。
So it's like a mailbox for your phone.
它就像你手机上的一个邮箱。
That's right.
没错。
Where you leave messages, obviously not text messages but you leave voice messages.
你可以在那里留言，显然不是短信，而是语音留言。
That's right.
没错。
So I'm sorry I cannot answer the phone right now.
所以“对不起，我现在不能接电话。”
Please leave a message after the beep.
“请在哔声后留言。”
That's my voicemail message.
这就是我的语音信箱留言。
That's right.
没错。
So it's actually a very useful thing.
所以这其实是一个非常有用的东西。
We'll talk about that a little bit later.
我们稍后会再谈谈这个。
But let's take a look at our next service.
但让我们看看下一个服务。
We also want to get call waiting.
我们还想要呼叫等待。
All right.
好的。
So this is a very interesting service.
这是一个非常有趣的服务。
I don't know if they have this in other parts of the world but in America if I'm talking
我不知道世界其他地方有没有，但在美国，如果我在和Marco你通电话，
on the phone to you Marco and we're having a nice conversation but then my mom calls,
我们聊得很开心，但这时我妈妈打电话来，
when I'm talking I hear beep, beep, beep.
我通话时会听到哔、哔、哔的声音。
I hear some sounds and that means someone else is trying to call you.
我听到一些声音，这意味着有人正在试图打给你。
That's right.
没错。
So you can't hear this but I can hear this and that means if I want to talk to my mom
所以你听不到这个，但我能听到，这意味着如果我想和我妈妈说话，
I'll say, hey Marco listen, someone else is calling, can I call you tomorrow?
我会说：“嘿Marco，听着，有人打电话来了，我明天再打给你行吗？”
That's right.
没错。
So actually call waiting is a very useful service because the person that's calling
所以实际上呼叫等待是一个非常有用的服务，因为打给你的人
you will never get a busy signal.
永远不会听到忙音。
You'll always see them available.
你总是显示为可接通状态。
But the good thing is that you can switch between calls.
但好处是你可以切换通话。
So I could say, hey Marco listen, I think that's my mom, can you hold, can you wait,
所以我可以这样说：“嘿Marco，听着，我想那是我妈妈，你能等一下吗，你能等一会儿吗，
I will be right back and then I push a button and then I can talk to my mom and then my
我马上回来。”然后我按一个按钮，就可以和我妈妈通话，然后我妈妈
mom says, okay I'll talk to you later, I push a button and then Marco you're there.
说：“好的，我晚点再跟你说。”我再按一个按钮，然后Marco你还在线上。
That's right.
没错。
Very useful service as well.
这也是一个非常有用的服务。
Now let's take a look at our next service that we are also getting as part of this package.
现在让我们看看下一个服务，也是这个套餐里包含的。
We are getting three-way calling.
我们有三方通话。
So from the name of this we can think of three people talking.
从名字上我们可以想到三个人在通话。
So maybe Marco you want to talk to my mom too.
所以也许Marco你也想和我妈妈聊聊。
So we can talk and then we add another person so you can call a third phone number, one,
所以我们可以通话，然后再加上另一个人，这样你就可以拨打第三个电话号码，一个，
two, three, me, you and someone else and the three of us can talk at the same time.
两个，三个，我、你和另一个人，我们三个人可以同时通话。
That's right.
没错。
So it's kind of a way of having a small conference between three people.
这有点像三个人之间开一个小型会议的方式。
That's right.
没错。
And so this is what you can do with three-way calling.
这就是三方通话能做的事情。
You can call two people simultaneously and talk to them at the same time.
你可以同时拨打两个人，并与他们同时通话。
So a lot of great services here.
这里有很多很棒的服务。
I think we've learned a couple of different things.
我想我们学到了几件不同的事情。
Why don't we review it and listen to the dialogue again.
我们不如回顾一下，再听一遍对话。
Telco Mobile, how can I help you?
Telco Mobile，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I'd like to activate my voicemail service please.
是的，我想激活我的语音邮件服务。
Certainly, sir.
当然可以，先生。
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services, call waiting
我们目前有一个特别促销活动，包括语音邮件服务、呼叫等待
and also three-way calling.
以及三方通话。
Sure, that sounds great.
好的，听起来不错。
Are there any other fees?
还有其他费用吗？
Not at all.
完全没有。
No hidden fees or surcharges.
没有隐藏费用或附加费。
It is a flat monthly rate.
这是一个固定的月费率。
Perfect.
完美。
I also wanted to know if there's any call forwarding service.
我还想知道有没有呼叫转移服务。
I am usually out of town and would like my calls to be forwarded to a local number.
我经常出差，希望我的电话能转接到一个本地号码。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然有。
We can activate all these services in about an hour.
我们可以在大约一小时内激活所有这些服务。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's keep on going here towards the last half of our dialogue.
现在我们继续往下，进入对话的后半部分。
Let's take a look at some more words on Language Takeaway Part 2.
让我们看看“语言要点第二部分”中的更多词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So this first phrase in Language Takeaway Part 2 is hidden fees.
所以“语言要点第二部分”中的第一个短语是“隐藏费用”。
Hidden fees.
隐藏费用。
What are these?
这些是什么？
The operator guarantees that there are no hidden fees.
客服保证没有隐藏费用。
So this is usually what we call the fine print, the small fees that we don't really know about.
这通常就是我们所说的“细则”，那些我们不太了解的小额费用。
So they say, oh, it costs $3 a month, but you have small little hidden fees.
所以他们说，哦，每月只需3美元，但还有一些小小的隐藏费用。
Like if you're late on a payment, they'll charge you an extra dollar or if you use the
比如如果你延迟付款，他们会额外收你一美元，或者如果你使用
service too much, they'll charge you another extra dollar.
服务太多，他们也会再额外收你一美元。
Right.
对。
So a fee is something that you pay, all right, and something that is hidden means you cannot
所以“费用”是你需要支付的东西，而“隐藏”的意思是你看
see it.
不到它。
And so like you're saying with this example, there are many, many conditions, many, many
就像你在这个例子中说的，有很多很多条件，很多很多
different things, rules that we have to follow.
不同的事情，我们必须遵守的规则。
And if we don't follow those rules exactly, then maybe this company that provides the
如果我们没有完全遵守这些规则，那么提供
phone service will ask us for more and more money.
电话服务的公司可能会向我们索要越来越多的钱。
That's right.
没错。
And actually it has to do a lot with our next word where she said that there are also no
实际上，这和我们下一个词有很大关系，她说也没有
surcharges.
附加费。
Okay, so a surcharge is an extra amount of money that you have to pay.
好的，所以“附加费”是你必须支付的额外金额。
So we say that this service has no hidden fees or surcharges.
所以我们说这项服务没有隐藏费用或附加费。
So that means that we don't have to pay anything additional to what we are already paying.
这意味着我们不需要支付任何超出我们已支付金额的额外费用。
For example, some companies will say, okay, pay us $10 and you get your new cell phone
例如，有些公司会说，好的，付给我们10美元，你就能得到你的新手机
phone plan.
套餐。
But to activate your service is another $5.
但要激活你的服务，还需要另外5美元。
So the total price is $15 and that's, that's a surcharge.
所以总价是15美元，这就是附加费。
It's an extra fee that you have to pay.
这是你必须支付的额外费用。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And continuing on the topic of money, she says it is a flat monthly rate, a flat monthly
继续关于钱的话题，她说这是一个固定的月费率，固定的月
rate.
费率。
Well, monthly is an adverb that tells us how often we pay.
嗯，“每月”是一个副词，告诉我们支付的频率。
We pay one time every month.
我们每个月支付一次。
But this term flat rate is very, very important and it happened.
但“固定费率”这个术语非常重要，而且它确实出现了。
We use this term a lot when we're talking about paying fees.
我们在谈论支付费用时经常使用这个术语。
So a flat rate means it does not change when you, for example, talk more on the phone.
所以固定费率意味着它不会改变，比如你打电话更多时。
That's right.
没错。
So you pay the same amount every month.
所以你每个月支付相同的金额。
That's right.
没错。
A clear example is probably your internet service provider.
一个明显的例子可能是你的互联网服务提供商。
You pay $20 a month and that's a flat rate.
你每月支付20美元，这就是固定费率。
If you use the internet 24 hours a day, nothing happens.
如果你一天24小时使用互联网，也不会有什么变化。
You don't pay more.
你不会付更多钱。
If you use it less, you still pay the same amount of money.
如果你用得少，你仍然支付相同的金额。
So what if I pay $10 normally, but this month I use the internet a lot and now I have to
那么如果我通常付10美元，但这个月我用了很多互联网，现在不得不
pay $15.
付15美元。
Is that a flat rate?
这是固定费率吗？
No, no, that's not a flat rate.
不，不，这不是固定费率。
Okay.
好的。
That's a change that that changes with my use.
这是根据我的使用量而变化的。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So now let's take a look at one last service that this man was also interested in getting
那么现在我们来看看这个人还想了解的最后一项服务。
and he says that he wants to get a call forwarding service.
他说他想开通呼叫转移服务。
He wants to forward his calls to a local number.
他想把电话转接到一个本地号码。
Okay.
好的。
So to forward something means to pass it along.
所以，“forward” 的意思是传递。
So call forwarding means that if I'm not available, for example, I'm not at home and someone calls
呼叫转移的意思是，如果我不在，比如我不在家，有人打电话到我家，
my home, there's no one there to talk to the person that's calling, then maybe I could
家里没人接听，那么我可能
have a call forwarding service that will make the call go to my cellular phone.
会使用呼叫转移服务，让电话转到我的手机上。
All right.
好的。
So the call forwarding means that the call will travel to another phone.
所以呼叫转移意味着电话会转到另一部电话上。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, this is what call forwarding is and the word to forward, as you said, to
所以正如你所说，这就是呼叫转移的意思，而“forward”这个词，正如你所说，是
pass along, maybe many of you have done it in your emails.
传递的意思，可能很多人都在邮件里做过。
When you get maybe a nice message, you forward it to more of your friends and this is the
当你收到一条好消息时，你会把它转发给更多朋友，这和
exact same definition.
这里的定义完全一样。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So you have one message and you pass it on to someone else.
所以你有一条消息，然后把它传给另一个人。
And so in call forwarding, you normally have this service if you're often on business trips
在呼叫转移中，如果你经常出差
or traveling, you're out of town.
或旅行，不在城里，通常会用到这项服务。
That's right.
没错。
It's very, very helpful for people who are not in one place all the time.
对于不总待在一个地方的人来说，这非常非常有帮助。
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
那我们最后再听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Telco Mobile, how can I help you?
电信移动，有什么可以帮您的？
Yes, I'd like to activate my voicemail service, please.
是的，我想开通语音信箱服务。
Certainly, sir.
好的，先生。
We currently have a special promotion where we include voicemail services, call waiting
我们目前有一个特别优惠，包含语音信箱、呼叫等待
and also three-way calling.
和三方通话服务。
Sure.
好的。
That sounds great.
听起来不错。
Are there any other fees?
还有其他费用吗？
Not at all.
完全没有。
No hidden fees or surcharges.
没有隐藏费用或附加费。
It is a flat monthly rate.
这是固定的月费。
Perfect.
太好了。
I also wanted to know if there's any call forwarding service.
我还想问一下有没有呼叫转移服务。
I am usually out of town and would like my calls to be forwarded to a local number.
我经常出差，希望电话能转接到一个本地号码。
Yes, of course.
是的，当然有。
We can activate all these services in about an hour.
我们可以在大约一小时内开通所有这些服务。
So talking about all these services, it's very interesting because many of these services
说到这些服务，很有意思，因为很多服务
are not really available everywhere in the world.
并不是全世界都有的。
Like for example, voicemail.
比如语音信箱。
That's right.
没错。
So in China, no one really has voicemail.
在中国，几乎没人用语音信箱。
It's very strange for an American because you think, well, if I'm not home, I want to
这对美国人来说很奇怪，因为你会想，如果我不在家，我想
know why this person called.
知道这个人为什么打电话。
But oftentimes, you just have to call back and find out.
但很多时候，你只能回拨过去才知道。
That's right.
没错。
And actually, I really think that voicemail service is a very good thing, especially if
实际上，我真的觉得语音信箱服务是件好事，尤其是
you need to leave a message for someone.
当你需要给别人留言的时候。
You know, hey, we're at the restaurant.
比如，嘿，我们在餐厅。
Call me back when you have a chance.
有空给我回电话。
But also, call waiting.
还有呼叫等待。
I really, really hate to call someone and have the busy tone.
我真的很讨厌打电话时听到忙音。
And then you know that they're on the telephone, but you don't know when they will stop talking
然后你知道他们在打电话，但不知道他们什么时候
on the phone.
会挂断。
This really annoys me too, especially when I call for delivery food from a restaurant.
这也让我很烦，尤其是我打电话叫外卖的时候。
It's like, please answer your phone.
就像，拜托接电话吧。
But maybe someone's ordering a lot of food.
但也许别人正在点很多菜。
That's right.
没错。
So actually, these services are very common in the United States.
所以实际上，这些服务在美国很常见。
And I'm sure there are even more services now.
而且我肯定现在还有更多服务。
I know that you can have a telephone number, for example, in another country, but it'll
我知道你可以有一个其他国家的电话号码，但
ring in the United States.
电话会在美国响。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
Or you can connect your computer and your messaging service and all these things to
或者你可以把电脑、消息服务等等都
your phone.
连接到你的手机上。
So it's pretty technologically advanced.
所以技术相当先进。
But I'm very curious to know about you guys, our listeners, what kind of services for your
但我很好奇，你们，我们的听众，你们的手机
cell phone or for your landline do you have?
或座机都有哪些服务？
Do you have call forwarding or voicemail?
你们有呼叫转移或语音信箱吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye-bye.
再见。